Guide to the Chamberlain Family Collections 1862-2003 MS009 MS009 MS009
Cornwall Historical Society
Chamberlain Family Collections
1862-2003
Cornwall Historical Society
Heninger, Dorothy Field Chamberlain (1922-2000)
MS009
1 linear foot (2 boxes)
The Chamberlain Family collection contains documents connected to the interrelated Bennett, Borland, and Chamberlain families of Cornwall.
Provenance
The collection was donated by Cynthia F. Heninger to the Cornwall Historical Society in 2003 and organized by Michael Gannett.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
These papers realted to the families of Dorothy Borland (1898-1970) and Paul Hilliard Chamberlain (1897-1977), both of whom resided in Cornwall.
Scope and Content Note
The papers were formerly in the possession of Dorothy Field Chamberlain Heninger (1922-2000), and relate to the families of her parents, Dorothy Borland (1898-1970) and Paul Hilliard Chamberlain (1897-1977), both of whom resided in Cornwall.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into series:
Provenance
Bennett Family
Borland Family
Chamberlain Family
Miscellaneous
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Cornwall (Conn.); Deeds; Photographs; Correspondence; Receipts (financial records); Heninger, Dorothy Field Chamberlain (1922-2000)
- Personal Papers
  - Provenance
    - Correspondence between Michael Gannett and Cynthia F. Heninger, about donating items, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Partial inventory of collection, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bennett Family
    - Militia exemption of William Bennett, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - William Bennett note regarding wood on Coltsfoot Mtn., 1871 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - William Bennett receipt for washing machine, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - William Bennett receipt for sewing machine, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Registration for William Bennett’s bulldog, Jack, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ethel Bennett autograph book, 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - William Bennett receipt for milk cans and cooler, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - William Bennett account with C.E. Wilcox Sons, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter sent to William Bennett from Seth Pratt, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Edward Bennett receipt for flour and saws from C.S. Blake, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Receipt for Hattie H. Bennett’s horse, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - William Bennett receipt for buggy from Flynn Doyle, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - William Bennett receipt from Cornwall Bridge Iron Co., 1897 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Mrs. W.C. Bennett receipt for groceries from C.E. Wilcox and Sons, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - William Bennett receipt for calf from M.A. Hallock, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Edward Bennett receipt from Henry P. Liner, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - William Bennett estate medical bill from Dr. W. M. Curtiss, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - William Bennett estate statement from Cochrane Bros., 1898 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hattie Bennett receipt for meat from N. Dunbar, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - E.M. Bennett grocery book, 1903-1905 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Deed from Harriet A. Bennett to Harriet Bennett Loucks, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Deed from Harriet A. Bennett to Edward W. Bennett, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - War ration materials of Mrs. Edward Bennett, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - William Bennett receipt for horse from S. Trumbull, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - William Church Bennett childhood dictionary, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Borland Family
    - Dorothy C. Borland East Street School diploma, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Asa Borland tax booklets, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
    - Asa C. Borland handgun permits, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Asa C. Borland membership card in Connecticut Association of Postmasters, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Chamberlain Family
    - War Department local board information on Kenyon F. Chamberlain, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Harry B. Chamberlain car registration, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
    - Kenyon F. Chamberlain driver’s license, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Letter sent to Mrs. Paul Chamberlain from J. Rogers, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Dorothy Chamberlain report card, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Ethel B. Chamberlain sugar purchase certificates, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - War ration material of Paul H. Chamberlain, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Verses written by Montgomery Hall in memory of Harry Chamberlain, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - V-Mail sent from “Howard” to Mr. and Mrs. Paul Chamberlain, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
    - Newspaper clipping about donation of Kenyon F. Chamberlain’s beetle collection, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Invitation sent to Mrs. and Mrs. Chamberlain to attend Rumsey Hall exercises, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Chamberlain family photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 47-50)
    - Dorothy Chamberlain war ration booklets, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Miscellaneous
  - Cornwall Band of Hope secretary’s book, 1869-1877 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Deed between Fayette W. Pierce and Polly Wetmore, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Autograph book belonging to "Eddie", 1881-1882 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Monthly doctor’s statement between Dr. Irve L. Hamant and William Wilcox, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Arrest warrant for Charles Lane, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - First prize ribbon from Cornwall Agricultural Fair, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cornwall Auxiliary of the American Red Cross report, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - William H. Haskins driver’s license, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Civil Defense preparedness card, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cornwall Rod and Gun Club menu, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ration books, undated (Box 2, Folder 12-Nov)